bosch-automotive.com 2019-04-22

# Privacy statement

### 3\. Processing of personal data

3.1 · Categories of data processed 

Communications data (e.g., name, telephone number, e-mail address, address, IP address) is processed.

3.2 · Processing principles

Personal data is all information which refers to an identified or identifiable natural person, for example, names, addresses, telephone numbers or e-mail addresses, which are an expression of the identity of a person.

We process personal data only when there is a legal basis for doing so or you have granted us your consent in this regard, e.g., within the scope of registration.

3.3. · Purposes of processing and legal basis

We and the service providers contracted by us process your personal data for the following processing purposes:

3.3.1 Provision of this online presence

Legal basis: An overriding legitimate interest on our part in direct marketing, provided that this occurs in accordance with data protection requirements and the requirements of competition law

3.3.2 Responding to user inquiries within the scope of a contact form

Legal basis: An overriding legitimate interest on our part in marketing as well as in the improvement of our products and services, provided that this occurs in accordance with data protection requirements and the requirements of competition law and/or contract performance or consent

3.3.4 Investigation of disruptions and for security reasons

Legal basis: Fulfillment of our legal obligations in the area of data security and an overriding legitimate interest in the elimination of disruptions and the security of our services.

3.3.7 Assertion and defense of our rights

Legal basis: A legitimate interest on our part in asserting and defending our rights.

3.4 · Log files

Whenever you use the Internet, specific information is automatically transmitted by your Internet browser and is stored by us in so-called “log files”.

We store the log files for a brief period to detect disruptions and for security reasons (e.g., clarification of attempted attacks) and delete them afterwards. Log files which must be kept longer for evidentiary purposes are exempt from deletion until final clarification of the respective incident and can be transmitted to investigative authorities on a case-by-case basis.

Log files are also used (without or without complete IP address) for purposes of analysis; in this regard, see the section "Web analysis" (see No. 5).

In particular, the following information is stored in the log files:

  * IP address (internet protocol address) of the terminal device from which the online presence is being accessed;
  * Internet address of the website from which the online presence was accessed (so-called origin or referrer URL);

  * Name of the service provider via which the online presence is accessed;
  * Date, time, and duration of retrieval;
  * Quantity of data transferred;
  * Operating system and information about the Internet browser used, including installed add-ons (e.g., for the Flash player);
  * http status code (e.g., "inquiry successful” or ”requested file not found”).

3.5 Transmission of data Name of the files and/or information retrieved;

3.5.1 Transmission of data to other responsible parties

As a rule, we transmit your personal data to other responsible parties only insofar as this is necessary for performance of the contract, if we or the third party have an overriding legitimate interest in transmitting the data or you have consented to this. Details regarding the legal basis may be found in the section “Purposes of processing and legal basis” (see No. 3.3). Third parties may also be other Bosch group companies. If data is transmitted to third parties on the basis of an overriding legitimate interest, this is explained in this privacy policy.

In addition, data may be transmitted to other responsible parties insofar as we are obligated to do so on account of legal regulations or an enforceable administrative or judicial order.

3.5.2 Transmission of data to service providers

We use external service providers for tasks such as marketing services, programming, data hosting, and hotline services. We have chosen these service providers carefully and supervise them on a regular basis, especially their careful handling and safeguarding of the data stored at these service providers. We bind all service providers to confidentiality and compliance with the legal regulations. Service providers may also be other Bosch group companies.

3.5.3 Transmission to recipients outside the EEA

We may also transmit personal data to recipients located outside the EEA in so-called “third countries”. In this case, we make certain prior to transmission that either an adequate level of data protection exists at the recipient’s (e.g., on the basis of an adequacy decision by the EU Commission for the respective country or agreement of so-called “EU standard contractual clauses of the European Union” with the recipient) or your consent to transmission is on file.

You can obtain from us an overview of the recipients in third countries and a copy of the specifically contracted provisions for ensuring an adequate level of data protection. For this, please use the information in the section “Responsible entity and contact” (see No. 2).

3.6 Duration of storage; retention periods

As a rule, we store your data as long as this is necessary to provide our online presence and the associated services or as long as we have a legitimate interest in continued storage (e.g., we may still have a legitimate interest in postal marketing even after fulfillment of a contract). In all other cases, we delete your personal data with the exception of data that we must continue to store in order to fulfill legal obligations (e.g., we are obligated to retain contracts and invoices for a specific period because of mandatory storage periods defined in tax law and commercial law).
